nimbuzzout.com 2016-11-26

# Nimbuzz: World's Best Instant Messenger

#### Nimbuzz Privacy Statement

Nimbuzz is committed to respecting your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal information, communications data and communications content and this Privacy Statement sets out what data Nimbuzz collects and how we use and protect it. “Nimbuzz” is Nimbuzz Netherlands BV, a Dutch company, with its registered office at Koningskade 40, 2596AA Den Haag, The Netherlands, and is responsible for the data processing.

IF YOU ARE UNDER 16 YEARS OLD YOU SHOULD DISCUSS THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT WITH A PARENT OR LEGAL GUARDIAN, AND ENSURE THAT THEY AGREE WITH NIMBUZZ’S USE OF YOUR INFORMATION.

This Statement also forms a part of the Agreement between you and us for the use of the Nimbuzz Services and Nimbuzz Website, as explained in the Terms of Use. Capitalised terms used in this Privacy Statement are defined in the Terms of Use. By using the Nimbuzz Services or the Website you consent to our using your data as explained in this Statement.

We may amend this Privacy Statement by posting a new version on the Website and/or notifying you in some other way as set out below.

##### 1\. What types of personal information does nimbuzz collect?

In connection with the provision of the Nimbuzz Services (including the Nimbuzz Paid Services), Nimbuzz may gather and process information about you, including the following types of information:  

  * __Your personal data including contact and registration details (name, User ID, address, telephone, mobile, email address etc.) and profile data (age, sex, pastimes, etc.);
  * __status updates or public data you post within the Nimbuzz Services;
  * __payment data including your credit or debit card billing address etc.,
  * __your phonebook, names and addresses, lists of contacts;
  * __login data including for Third Party Services accessible through the Nimbuzz Services;
  * __network and technical data (IP addresses, network operator, Device ID data, Device operating system, cookies, etc.);
  * __data in relation to use of Nimbuzz games or programs;
  * __anonymous data on the approximate location of your device (e.g., from the cell ID data of your mobile network or GPS services);
  * __communications contents (e.g., calls, chats, IMs, files share
  * __Communications data (e.g., the duration of the call, the number calling, the number called, etc.); and
  * __questionnaires or survey results and information regarding use of the Nimbuzz Services.

##### 2\. How and why does nimbuzz use your personal information?

Our reasons for collecting information relating to you or your Device are to enable Nimbuzz (or sometimes other data processors selected by Nimbuzz) to provide the Nimbuzz Services through the Nimbuzz application or other applications provided by Nimbuzz to you in an effective and satisfactory way, as follows:  

  * __processing your log-ins, messages and calls and enabling the other features of the Nimbuzz Services;
  * __showing your profile information on the Nimbuzz Services: please note that your profile information is provided by you voluntarily and under your sole responsibility;
  * __receiving payment from you for Nimbuzz Paid Services, and sending you a receipt or communications regarding your purchases or orders;
  * __providing you with customer support, responding to questions and helping to resolve problems;
  * __informing you about service updates or problems;
  * __resolving disputes;
  * __verifying your identity;
  * __for legal reasons, e.g., checking that you comply with the Terms of Use and Nimbuzz policies, and preventing crime and fraud;
  * __customizing, understanding users’ use of, and improving the Nimbuzz Services and Nimbuzz Website (this includes customization of advertising based on your location, or features such as indicating when you were last online, notifying your contacts when you are playing a Nimbuzz game or permitting you to invite them to participate in Nimbuzz games); and
  * __informing you of additional products, services and offers provided by Nimbuzz.

Nimbuzz stores the personal information in different data files kept on servers based in the Netherlands. Nimbuzz will take all reasonable measures to ensure security of the data, including where such servers may be operated by third party data processors under Nimbuzz’s responsibility.

If we provide a method for you to invite friends to join Nimbuzz, then their contact information will only be used for the purposes of automatically generating a message to these potential Nimbuzz users. Nimbuzz Services also have a function that can check the names and phone numbers in your address book against the list of Nimbuzz users and informs you of existing contacts that are already registered for Nimbuzz Services and with whom you may want to connect. If you are already in the address book of other Nimbuzz Services users they be informed that you are a Nimbuzz user you so that they can decide whether to connect with you.

If we process data regarding the location of your Device then (i) in case of services such as allowing location requests from your Nimbuzz contacts, you will be able to switch this functionality on or off at any time within the Nimbuzz Services, and (ii) where this is used in order to provide advertising appropriate to your locality then we may provide this to our third party advertising partners but never in a form that you will be able to be identified from this data; and your acceptance of this privacy statement constitutes consent for this processing.

##### 3\. Does nimbuzz transfer your personal information to anyone else?

Nimbuzz does not sell, rent, trade or otherwise transfer any personal information, log-in information, communications data or communications content to any third party without your express permission (unless it is obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities) except as set out in this Statement.

Nimbuzz needs to provide certain information to third parties who assist Nimbuzz in providing elements of the Nimbuzz Services. So, for example, in order to enable you to access to voice calling services, Nimbuzz may need to provide your mobile number to the provider of such calling services, or to collect payment from you for the Nimbuzz Paid Services Nimbuzz may need to provide such data to a payment processor. Under their contracts with Nimbuzz they are required to store and process your information in accordance with similar standards of protection of your data as applied by Nimbuzz.

If any authority lawfully requests Nimbuzz or one of Nimbuzz’s partners to retain and provide personal information, communications content and/or communications or technical data, or permit monitoring or interception, Nimbuzz and/or its partner may comply with that request without being obliged to inform you.

Nimbuzz operates internationally and may transfer the data for processing in different countries, including by Nimbuzz group companies, outside of your home country.

##### 4\. What items are placed on your device when using the nimbuzz services or website?

In order to use most of the Nimbuzz Services, you will need to install the relevant software on your Device. This software enables you to make and receive communications using your mobile network or the internet and sends the necessary communications data, and other data that you define (e.g., profile or status updates, community log-in data) between your Device and the network.

In addition, for web-based Nimbuzz Services, “cookies” may be used. Cookies are pieces of information stored on your Device in order to enable web-based applications to recognize who you are or your preferences (e.g., what language version of the Website you usually use) and provide Nimbuzz with information about the use of its Websites).

Most internet browsers allow you to prevent your Device from accepting or using cookies or require your permission each time a cookie is received. Please note that some personalized Nimbuzz Services may not be available if you choose to disable cookies.

Advertisements appearing on Nimbuzz Services or Websites may be provided by Nimbuzz’s advertising partners who may use cookies, web beacons, and/or other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous statistics. The information obtained in this way (e.g., how many times the Website is visited, how many times you see a particular advert) is used to deliver adverts to you. In addition, we may use profile information about you (e.g., your gender, age or pastimes) to provide advertisements that are more likely to be of interest to you, including by combining with other available information about you. We may share your information with advertisers or other third parties that assist us with these types of services, when we have either removed from it anything that personally identifies you, or encoded or combined it with other information so that it no longer personally identifies you.

##### 5\. Your user profile

Your user profile is the information you decide to provide when you create or manage your Nimbuzz Services account (e.g., your Nimbuzz user ID, full name, address, telephone numbers, gender, date of birth, language, status, and any other information that you decide to make available). Nimbuzz stores your user profile centrally on a secure server. This information is also visible to other Nimbuzz users. You control your user profile and decide what (if anything) to make public. You can access your user profile within the Nimbuzz Services in order to access, change, correct, complete or remove information. Nimbuzz may remove unsuitable or illegal material at any time from your profile or other postings in accordance with the Terms of Use.

##### 6\. Third party websites and platforms

Nimbuzz Websites and Nimbuzz Services may contain links that will let you access Third Party Services such as another website, platform or application. Third Party Services are outside Nimbuzz’s control and not covered by this Privacy Statement. Nimbuzz accepts no responsibility or liability for Third Party Services. You should take care before providing any personal information to anyone and in these cases especially to review the applicable privacy statements or policies.

Certain Nimbuzz Services use the Google Places service provided by Google, Inc. When you use these services then you also agree to the Google Privacy Policy as set out at <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

Where Nimbuzz provides the ability for you to log-in to Third Party Services using your Nimbuzz account credentials (a feature known as “Nimbuzz Connect”), then you will be asked to agree to this in each case. The particular information that those third parties will be able to access will be indicated at the time of asking for your agreement but will normally include items such as your Nimbuzz ID, nickname, email, profile picture, friend list, personal message (status) and online/offline presence.

Remember that use of Third Party Services may in addition be subject to your signing up for an account with and accepting the terms and conditions of the relevant third party, including provisions relating to processing of personal data, which may differ from Nimbuzz’s policies and for which Nimbuzz is not responsible. You can view, manage and block the third party services that use your Nimbuzz ID by logging into your Nimbuzz profile at any time. If your Nimbuzz friends sign up for third party services using Nimbuzz Connect, then the information they share may include your Nimbuzz ID so that they can also connect with you on the third party service.

##### 7\. How does nimbuzz protect your personal information?

Nimbuzz takes appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect the personal information and communications data provided to them or collected by them. For example, your personal and communications data can only be accessed by authorized Nimbuzz staff that need to have access to this data in order for their work.

Nimbuzz takes technical measures to protect the confidentiality of the content of communications sent over the Nimbuzz Services, subject to all applicable obligations and exceptions under applicable law.

##### 8\. Contacting You

Nimbuzz may contact you to notify you of issues and faults with the Nimbuzz Services, and if you are considered to have breached any of the terms of your Agreement with Nimbuzz or if another person makes a complaint about your use of the Nimbuzz Services (e.g., a claim that you have infringed their rights in some way).

Nimbuzz may also use email, SMS or the Nimbuzz Services to keep you up to date with news about the Nimbuzz Services that you use and/or other Nimbuzz Services unless you have opted out of receiving this information. If you do not want to be kept informed in this way, please contact Nimbuzz at support@nimbuzz.com.

Nimbuzz may occasionally ask you to provide information on your experiences with the Nimbuzz Services. Any such feedback will always be voluntary and will be used only for the purposes of measuring and improving the quality of the Nimbuzz Services and Website and not stored as personal information or combined with any of your other personal information.

##### 9\. Can this privacy statement be changed?

Nimbuzz reserves the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time by notifying you by any reasonable means or by publishing the modified Privacy Statement at http://www.nimbuzz.com/en/legal/privacy_statement. The modified Privacy Statement will become effective thirty days from such publication or notification, unless you expressly accept the modified Privacy Statement earlier. Such express acceptance by you, or your continued use of any Nimbuzz Service after expiry of the notice period of thirty days, shall constitute your consent to the modified Privacy Statement.

##### 10\. What are your rights and how can you contact nimbuzz?

You have the right to access and, if necessary, to rectify your personal information. To exercise your right to view, correct, complete or remove your personal information, please contact Nimbuzz at support@nimbuzz.com. After verifying your identity and provided your request is legal, within a reasonable period of time Nimbuzz will fulfil your request.

You may also ask Nimbuzz to stop processing your personal information. However, please note that this will most likely prevent you from using some or all of the Nimbuzz Services. You can exercise your right to prevent further processing of your personal information by contacting Nimbuzz at support@nimbuzz.com.

##### 11\. How long is your personal information kept by nimbuzz?

Nimbuzz will retain your information for as long as is necessary to carry out any of the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement and comply with applicable legislation, and any applicable orders of regulatory bodies or courts.

©Nimbuzz Netherlands BV, all rights reserved. Last revised: 21 October 2014
